http://www.calbarrie.com/privacy-policy/

HomeAboutSustainabilityCompliance ServicesElectrical Compliance ServicesPAT TestingFixed Installation TestingElectrical Remedial WorksThermal ImagingFire & Light Compliance ServicesEmergency Light TestingFire Extinguisher Testing & ServicingFire Alarm TestingTestimonialsCase StudiesCustomer LoginNewsJobsContactSearchPrivacy PolicyHome / Privacy PolicyCalbarrie Compliance Services Limited is an electrical compliance company providing electrical testing and inspection services. Our registered address is Barrington House, Kingsditch Lane, Cheltenham GL51 9NN.  This Privacy Policy explains the type of data that we collect and how we use it. Information that we collect We only collect data about our customers for the purpose of providing essential business to business services required for statutory compliance. We do not collect personal or financial information, or any data that we do not need in order to provide our services and manage our contract with you. The information we collect includes your name and your business contact details including your business email address. We will directly collect information when you contact us to enquire about our services or place an order with us.How we use information We use the information as follows:to maintain our relationship with you whilst you are a customer;to process orders and provide agreed services to you;for invoicing, processing payments, account set up and maintenance;to communicate with you, including to respond to information requests/ enquiries submitted and/or to obtain your feedback on our services;for record keeping, statistical analysis and internal reporting;to ensure data security and to provide you with access to secure areas of our Websites;to notify you about changes to our services;to decide on and notify you about price changes;to monitor the quality of our services;for logistical purposes, including to plan and monitor scheduling programmes;to investigate any complaint you make;to provide evidence in any dispute or anticipated dispute between you and us;to protect the rights, property, and/or safety of Calbarrie Compliance Services Ltd, its employees and others. Marketing Your agreement to the use of your information for direct marketing purposes is optional. We may send you information in relation to our services by phone and email unless you have told us not to. You can choose to opt out of receiving direct marketing information from us at any time by:clicking the ‘Opt out’ link at the bottom of any Calbarrie Compliance Services Ltd marketing email you receiveadvising our account manager that you would like to ‘Opt out’ if they contact youcompleting our contact form on our website at http://www.calbarrie.com/contact/emailing us at info@calbarrie.comcalling us on 01242 587080.Legal basis for processing The legal bases we rely upon to use the information is legitimate interest and contractual obligation. The legal bases in which we process information are:for the performance of a contract with you for the provision of services or to take steps at your request prior to entering into this contract;to comply with legal obligations, including in relation to health and safety and environmental legislation, performing anti-money laundering, terrorism prevention and sanctions screening checks, complaints and investigations or litigation;for our legitimate interests in: – processing orders and supplying our services – managing your account (including processing payments) and our relationship with you, and communicating with you – sending direct marketing where you have not provided consent but the marketing communication is in respect of our services and your legal obligation as an employer to comply with electrical compliance; – our internal business purposes which may include processing for the purposes of: record keeping, reporting and statistics, data security, to ensure the quality of our services, investigating and responding to queries and complaints, fraud detection and prevention, risk management, recruitment and training of our personnel, and protecting our rights, property and safety (and that of others).You can object to processing carried out on the basis of our legitimate interests at any time by emailing info@calbarrie.com. See also ‘Your Rights’. How we may share information All the data we process is processed by our staff in the UK. We will not share data with any third party other than where we are contractually obliged to do so in order to deliver our services to you or legally obliged to do so. We will not sell data to any third party. Third parties we may need to share information with are:Calbarrie sub-contractors and suppliers who are providing services to you on our behalfour accountants, auditors, lawyers or similar advisers when we ask them to provide us with professional advice;emergency services in the event that we need to report accidents or incidents or request emergency assistance;any Government Department, public body or other third party where we believe in good faith that the law requires this; in the interests of public health and safety; or in order to protect the rights, property, or safety of Calbarrie, its employees or others;any other third parties, if authorised by you to do so.How long we keep your informationWe retain data only for as long as is necessary. Different laws require us to keep different data for different periods of time. We may on occasions contact you to make sure that your data is accurate and up-to-date. When determining the relevant retention periods, we will take into account factors including legal obligation(s) under applicable law to retain data for a certain period of time; (potential) disputes, and guidelines issued by relevant data protection authorities. Otherwise, we securely erase your information once it is no longer needed. For more information on our retention schedules see our Data Protection Policy. Information for employment We only collect data about applicants and employees for the purpose of managing your contract of employment. We will not collect any data that we do not need in order to provide our services as an employer. The information we collect includes your basic personal data including name and contact details. To enable us to fulfil our duties as an employer we may on rare occasions ask you for sensitive personal data such as health information. You may give your data to us directly, such as on an application form or in a contract of employment, or we may collect it from another source such as a recruitment agency. The lawful bases we rely on for using personal information in our recruitment and employment processes are:ConsentLegitimate interestVital interestsLegal obligationContractual obligationApplicants: We only use information about an applicant that is required to process their application. If we need to disclose information to a third party, for example where we want to take up a reference, we will not do so without your express consent, unless the disclosure is required by law. Information about unsuccessful candidates will be held for 12 months after the recruitment exercise has been completed, it will then be destroyed or deleted.Employees: We will compile a hard copy folder and system file relating to all Calbarrie employees. The information contained in this will be kept secure and will only be used in order for us to manage your contract of employment with us. Personal data is only used for processes that you would reasonably expect i.e. completion of payroll or salary, monitoring progress, reviewing training and competency. Sensitive data such as next of kin contact details and medical issues are only available to Senior Managers in the HR Team and are used for legitimate emergency situations. Your personal data is required by law and/or a contractual requirement. We may on occasions contact you to make sure that your data is accurate and up-to-date.Leavers: When you leave Calbarrie your hard copy folder and system file will be retained for a period of time relevant to the information stored. These files will be removed from the live system and will be accessed only by relevant Directors.8. Your rightsYou have the following data protection rights:The right to be informed about the personal data Calbarrie Compliance Services Ltd processes on you;The right of access to the personal data we process on you;The right to rectification of your personal data;The right to erasure of your personal data in certain circumstances;The right to restrict processing of your personal data;The right to data portability in certain circumstances;The right to object to the processing of your personal data that was based on a public or legitimate interest;The right not to be subjected to automated decision making and profiling; andThe right to withdraw consent at any time.You can request to view, correct or remove your data at anytime by contacting our Compliance Manager. For more information on our retention schedules see our Data Protection Policy.Contacting us If  you have any questions or concerns about how we have handled your personal data you can contact our Compliance Manager, Michelle Roy, by telephoning 01242 587080, by emailing michelleroy@calbarrie.com or writing to her at Barrington House, Kingsditch Lane, Cheltenham, GL51 9NN. You also have the right to report any concerns with the Information Commissioner’s Office on 0303 123 1113 or at https://ico.org.uk/concerns/.  Contact UsHEAD OFFICE Calbarrie Compliance Services Barrington House Kingsditch Lane Cheltenham GL51 9NNT: 0844 335 6573 E: info@calbarrie.comContact UsName*
First
Last Company*Telephone Number*Email*Which services are you interested in? (Please tick all that apply)*
Portable Appliance Testing (PAT)
Fixed Installation Testing
Electrical Remedial Works & Repairs
Thermal Imaging
Fire Alarm Testing
Fire Extinguisher Testing, Servicing & Supply
Fire Risk Assessment
Emergency Lighting TestingCommentsThis field is for validation purposes and should be left unchanged.
Calbarrie ServicesPAT TestingFixed Installation TestingElectrical Remedial WorksThermal ImagingEmergency Light TestingFire Extinguisher Testing & ServicingFire Alarm TestingAccreditation The UK's No.1 Provider of Electrical Compliance TestingELECTRICAL SERVICESElectrical Compliance ServicesElectrical Remedial WorksThermal ImagingFixed Installation TestingPAT Testing FIRE & LIGHTING SERVICESFire & Light Compliance ServicesEmergency Light TestingFire Extinguisher Testing & ServicingFire Alarm TestingHEAD OFFICECheltenham Office Barrington House Kingsditch Lane Cheltenham GL51 9NN T 0844 335 6573 E info@calbarrie.comLegalPrivacy PolicyRegional OfficesCalbarrie Devon & CornwallCalbarrie Glasgow © Calbarrie Compliance Services Ltd, Registered in England & Wales, Barrington House, Cheltenham, Gloucestershire GL51 9NN. Company No: 6727566
